The Max Smith Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Articles, 1922-1923; no date; Series II; 1 Box
  B. A handwritten copy of an article by Lyman ---? on Alessander Dolci, no date
  - Articles by Max Smith, II.A
    - Articles on Arthur Toscanini, 1922; 1925; no date; 8 items; typed copies (mostly rough drafts) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Articles and reviews of operas and opera singers, 1922-1923; no date; ca. 20 items; typed copies (mostly rough drafts) (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Articles and critical reviews of miscellaneous concerts, 1922-1923; no date; ca. 10 items; typed copies (mostly rough drafts) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Articles by Others, II.B
    - Article by Lyman ---? on Alessander Dolci, no date; 1 item; handwritten copy (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1903-1923; no date; Series III; 1/2 Box
  This section covers many varied items, including a photo, menu, contract, list of subscription rates for concerts in New York, etc. Items included here are not organized in any special fashion, but are listed individually in the register for quick identification.
  - Vicennial of Smith's class, 1918; photo (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - to Smith as Music Critic to meet Heinrich Conried, 1918 Feb 27; invitation (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - from Restaurant Lüchow in New York City, 1903 Apr 11; menu (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - from burial service for Henry Edward Krehbiel, 1923 Mar 23; bulletin (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - between CBS and Adolf Busch, 1931 Jan 3; contract (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - concerning contract between Adolf Busch and CBS, no date; 6 typed pages (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - to City Editor of the New York American, concerning musician's union, 1923 Mar 6; typed letter signed (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - announcing that no compositions or records by Toscanini, Damrosch, Bauer, et al. will be played on German radio station due to appeal by certain Jewish musicians, no date; typed sheet (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - listing subscription rates for concerts at Carnegie, City Symphony, Symphony Society, etc., no date [early 20s]; 8 typed sheets (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - list of subscribers to the Opera Club, no date; typed sheet (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - miscellaneous notes, no date; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - writ between Max Smith and Oscar Hammerstein, Jan 30, 1909; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings, 16 pages (xerox) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    including performance announcements, programs and reviews of performances (primarily conducted by Toscanini)
  - Biographical information apparently written in response to a series of questions, 10 pages (Box 4, Folder 9)
    (composed on Hotel Astor, New York stationary)
  - Photographs, 7 items (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Concert programs from Teatro alla Scala - Toscanini conducting, 29 and 30 June 1925; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 11)